<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curriculums on Udani A. Wijewardhana</title>
    <link>/curriculum/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curriculums on Udani A. Wijewardhana</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="/curriculum/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Extra curricular activities</title>
      <link>/curriculum/curriculum/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/curriculum/curriculum/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Achievements and curricular activities:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully completed Dharmacharya Buddhist Teaching Examination in 2009 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head Prefect of Siri Wimalasiri Dhamma School in 2005 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;President of Buddhist Society of De Mazenod College in 2005 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leader of Eastern Music Group of De Mazenod College from 2004 to 2005 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Junior &amp;amp; Senior Prefect of De Mazenod College (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sangeet Visharad Degree offered from &amp;lsquo;Bathkande Sangeet Vidyapith&amp;rsquo;, Lucknow (India) conducted by &amp;lsquo;Gaandhaari Kala Nikethana&amp;rsquo; (Sri Lanka) and Passed with 1st Division (Rank 1 in Sri Lanka, 2012).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Musician 2007 of De Mazenod College (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colourswoman of Music 2006 &amp;amp; Colourswoman of Dancing 2004 of De Mazenod College (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Best Outstanding Student 2005 of Siri Wimalasiri Dhamma School (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Colourswoman of Table Tennis 2006 in Gampaha District (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All Island Table Tennis Championships of Under 14 in 1999 and Under 18 in 2003 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Champion of singing in the &amp;lsquo;Vesta 2011&amp;rsquo; talent competition organized by the Science Faculty, University of Colombo (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memberships:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Student member of statistical society Australia Inc. (2019-present).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of Mathematical Olympiad Program in 2013 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of Epsilon and Delta Mathematics Society, Art Circle &amp;amp; Photographic Circle in University of Colombo, Faculty of Science from 2010-2014 (Sri Lanka) .&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of Table-Tennis teams of Sangamitta College), Sri Lanka (1997-2000), De Mazenod College (2005-2007) &amp;amp; University of Colombo, Faculty of Science in 2011-2013 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Member of Mass Media Unit - Eastern music group &amp;amp; dancing group of De Mazenod College from 2001 to 2007 (Sri Lanka).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conferences and workshops:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Successfully completed Graduated Certificate of Research and Innovation Management.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented at Young Statistician Conference 2019 and participated for the Communicating with R Markdown workshop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented at Victorian Research Students&amp;rsquo; Meeting in Probability and Statistics 2019 and 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented at Building Bridges - FHAD Student Research Conference 2019 and 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attended for Student Training Two Days Workshop 2019 organized by Swinburne University (qualitative approaches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presented my PhD research overview at Virtual International Statistical Ecology Conference (vISEC2020)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
